Hi, we are happy to welcome you to take our RAG++ course.
If you have built a RAG-powered system or have developed a proof of concept
but lack the confidence to deploy it into production,
this course will help bridge that gap.
Over the last 21 months, we have been running wandbot,
a live customer support bot for weights and biases,
and we're excited to share what we have learned from the experience.
We will highlight what separates a good RAG system from a great one
by focusing on evaluation-driven development,
emphasizing the importance of an effective evaluation pipeline.
We will explore different metrics for evaluation,
like MRR, NDCG, and LLM evaluators.
We will also see how we can align an LLM evaluator with human feedback.
Next, we will dive into advanced RAG components for sophisticated data ingestion strategies,
effective metadata utilization, and query enhancement techniques like query decomposition.
We will improve retrieval quality using methods like metadata filtering,
routing, and re-ranking.
We also have two guest lecturers.
Charles from Weaviate will cover production-grade hybrid retrieval systems,
and Meor from Cohere will show how to incorporate tool-use capabilities into your RAG system.
The course is packed with practical insights to enhance response synthesis
and methods to optimize your RAG pipeline's latency.
By the end of this course, you will have the tools and confidence to take your RAG systems
from POC to production-led deployments.
We hope you enjoyed the course as much as we enjoyed creating it.