Before you get started, let us set you up to get the most out of this course.
Throughout the course we will be recommending useful tools.
However we will mainly be using Weave, Cohere and Weaviate.
Weave is a lightweight toolkit for tracking and evaluating your LLM applications.
We will be using Cohere family of models for text generation, re-ranking and embedding.
Cohere is also providing with free credits for this course.
Check out the instructions under this lesson to redeem your free Cohere API key for this
course.
Once you have the API keys, head over to the Colab notebook for this lesson.
We first install the required packages.
We then initialise our Weave client.
This is where you will put in your wandb API key.
We then set up our Cohere client.
We will then use the Cohere model to ask about retrieval augmented generation.
If everything works fine, you will have a Weave URL.
Let's head over to it.
This is a single trace of the Cohere client chat method.
We will automatically capture the inputs to the client as well as the generated response.
We also keep track of the used tokens and the time taken to complete the generation.
Now let's get started with the course.
Enjoy!