Hello and welcome to chapter 4 of our course, where we will be exploring query enhancement.
In this chapter, we'll discuss some powerful tools and techniques to enrich user queries for our RAG
systems. Query enhancement gives a RAG system a deep understanding of user intentions. It allows
your system to grasp the real meaning and intentions behind each query. We'll give you
the techniques to improve how a RAG system interprets and responds to user queries.
So let's get started. By the end of this chapter, you will have a comprehensive understanding of
query enhancement and its significance in RAG systems. We'll dive into four key techniques
that can significantly improve query processing capabilities. These aren't just theoretical
concepts. We'll examine their practical applications through our wandbot example.
We'll also share some best practices to effectively implement query enhancement in your
own RAG systems. This knowledge will be instrumental in enhancing a RAG system's capabilities.
So let's begin our exploration of query enhancement and its potential to elevate RAG performance.