This is a good time to talk about the role that large language models play in query enhancement.
While traditional NLP techniques have been the go-to for query enhancement,
in OneBot we use LLMs with function calling capabilities for our query enhancement.
Here's how it works. We prompt the LLM to enhance the user queries and generate structured outputs.
The LLM then gives a structured JSON that includes intent classification,
keyword extraction, and subquery generation.
We then use pydantic models to validate this output,
ensuring it meets our schema requirements.
This approach has significantly improved the accuracy of our intent classification
and keyword extraction steps. It allows for more nuanced query reformulation,
which is particularly effective when handling complex queries.
With this, we are able to provide more contextually relevant responses,
even for tricky technical queries. Using LLMs with function calling capabilities in
your query enhancement process can get you started without training NLP models from scratch,
giving your RAG system the extra boost of intelligence and flexibility it needs.