Let's start by understanding what query enhancement is and why it's so crucial for RAG systems.
Think of query enhancement as a skilled interpreter between the user and your RAG system.
It takes what the user says and refines it into something your system can better understand and
process. It's like giving your RAG system x-ray vision. Suddenly, it can see user intentions more
clearly, leading to more accurate information retrieval and more relevant responses.
Query enhancement helped us tackle some tricky challenges when we faced in wandbot. For instance,
when users ask ambiguous questions or when they fire off complex multi-part queries,
this technique has helped wandbot understand the nuances of what users are asking and reply with
precision. This has dramatically improved wandbot's ability to understand and respond to user queries,
consequently improving the overall user experience. So, as we dive deeper into this topic,
keep in mind that a good query enhancement system can be a game-changer for your RAG system's
performance and user satisfaction. Now, let's talk about the four key techniques that form the
backbone of effective query enhancement. Think of these techniques as the essential tools in your
query enhancement toolkit. First, we have conversation history utilization. This is like
giving your system a good memory. Next, there is intent recognition, which helps your system
understand the why behind a user's query. Then, we have keyword extraction, which helps extract
and inject domain knowledge into your user queries. And finally, there is query decomposition that
breaks complex queries into manageable parts for your system to process. In wandbot, we've
implemented all four of these techniques to ensure that we are getting the most out of our system.
As we explore each technique in detail, you'll see how they work together to improve your system's
ability to understand and process user queries. These tools are what allow your RAG system to go
from just seeing user words to truly understanding what the users are asking for. Let's dive into our
first technique, utilizing conversation history. Imagine trying to understand a movie by only
watching five random five-minute clips. Frustrating, right? That's what it's like for a RAG system to
try to understand queries without context. Utilizing conversation history is like giving
your system the ability to remember parts of the conversation. It helps maintain context across
multiple interactions, making responses more coherent and relevant. In wandbot, we use this
technique through chat history condensation and contextual query reformulation. Here's an example.
When a user asks a follow-up question about logging metrics, wandbot can look back at previous
interactions and remember that the user was asking about logging metrics with PyTorch specifically.
This allows it to respond in a more targeted way. This is especially useful in conversations that
often involve multiple turns and related questions. By utilizing conversation history, you're
essentially giving your RAG system a better memory, leading to more natural and conversational
interactions. Now let's talk about our second technique, intent recognition. It's our RAG system's
mind-reading ability. It helps the system in understanding the why behind the user's query.
Traditionally, we use NLP techniques like classification and sentiment analysis for this.
These models act like detectives analyzing the query to figure out what the user really wants.
In wandbot, we prompt an LLM to classify user queries into predefined intents. For instance,
when a user asks, how do I log metrics, wandbot classifies this under product features. This
classification is crucial because it guides the retrieval process. It points a system in the right
direction before it starts searching for information. By implementing intent recognition,
you're giving your RAG system the power to understand user needs more deeply.
This deeper understanding leads to more accurate and relevant responses,
significantly improving the user experience. Remember, the better your system understands
user intent, the more helpful and accurate its responses will be. Let's move on to our
third technique, keyword enhancement. Keyword extraction and expansion is a tried and tested
method in information retrieval for decades. It's part of many search engines and recommendation
systems we use daily. In the context of RAG systems, keyword extraction and expansion employs
machine learning algorithms to identify, extract, and enhance the most important words and phrases
from user queries. In wandbot, we adopted keyword and key phrase enhancements to improve domain
specificity. For example, our system extracts and injects key terms such as logging metrics,
experiment tracking, and 1 DB usage to the query, how do I log metrics? These enhanced keywords act
as lexical anchors guiding our system to the most relevant information in our knowledge base.
When you augment queries with such keywords and phrases, you ensure more relevant and accurate
information retrieval and ultimately more helpful responses for your users, especially when dealing
with domain-specific knowledge. Let's talk about our fourth technique, query decomposition.
Sometimes, user queries can be complex, like a puzzle with multiple pieces. Query decomposition
is our way of solving that puzzle. It involves breaking down complex user queries into simple,
more manageable subqueries and vector search queries. Let's look at an example. While initially
a query like how do I log metrics looks quite simple, it can be decomposed into specific
subqueries addressing different aspects of metric logging, like the steps involved, some examples,
and even best practices to follow. We also reformulate queries into vector search queries
optimized for our retrieval system. This is particularly effective when dealing with intricate
or multifaceted user queries. By revealing hidden needs and identifying implicit information,
query decomposition helps wandbot provide more comprehensive and accurate responses to user
inquiries. This ensures that all aspects of a query and complex system are addressed, giving
users a complete and satisfying answer. In a sense, query decomposition allows your
rag system to tackle even the most challenging queries with precision and thoroughness.