Hello and welcome to the hands-on session of chapter 4 of our course.
In this session, we'll explore query enhancement techniques.
First, we'll quickly set up the environment and load the semantically chunked data from chapter 3.
Now let's dive into the core of this chapter, the query enhancer.
This module performs three key tasks.
Language identification, detecting whether the query is in English, Japanese, or Korean.
Intent classification, determining if the query is relevant to our documentation.
And subquery generation, that is breaking down complex queries into smaller, more focused subqueries.
Let's look at an example from our query enhancer.
As you can see, it provides language detection, generates subqueries, and classifies the intent.
Next, we'll look at how we can leverage this information in our query-enhanced RAG pipeline.
The query-enhanced RAG pipeline leverages the enhancements in several ways.
It uses subqueries for multiple-query retrieval, broadening the scope of the relevant information.
It performs context deduplication to optimize LLM input.
And it implements an intent-based workflow, allowing us to handle off-topic or inappropriate queries better.
Next, let's compare the performance of our query-enhanced pipeline against a simple RAG pipeline from the previous chapter.
As you can see, both pipelines achieved similar correctness scores.
The simple RAG pipelines showed a slightly higher overall response quality, while the query-enhanced pipeline exhibited a significantly higher latency.
These results highlight important considerations when designing RAG systems.
Adding complexity doesn't always lead to immediate improvements in automated metrics.
The increased latency can significantly impact user experience.
We might need to improve our evaluation methods as we evolve our pipeline.
In conclusion, we've demonstrated the complexity of enhancing and evaluating RAG systems.
We also emphasize the need for balanced system design and efficient processing and comprehensive evaluation methods.
As you continue to develop RAG systems, keep these factors in mind and create more effective and user-friendly solutions.