Now let's look at an often overlooked aspect of query processing,
metadata extraction and how it enhances context in queries.
Metadata gives your RAG system additional contextual clues.
It's crucial for understanding the full picture of a user's query.
For example, in wandbot, we identify the language of the user's query.
This might seem simple, but it's actually quite crucial for our multilingual support.
Currently, wandbot can handle queries in English and Japanese.
By detecting the language, we can route queries to different language-specific resources.
For instance, if a query is detected as Japanese,
wandbot knows to retrieve relevant Japanese documentation and generate responses in Japanese.
This contextual adaptation leads to more consistent and appropriate responses.
It also streamlines the retrieval process, making our system more efficient.
By implementing metadata extraction, you are essentially fine-tuning your RAC system's
ability to understand and respond to queries in a more nuanced and contextually aware manner.