The tool use approach becomes more powerful when it involves working with complex queries,
and that requires tool use to run in a sequential manner, and we call it multi-step tool use.
So let's look at examples on what this means. So the example that we have seen in the previous
section is a single step scenario where, for example, in this case, you are given two tools.
One is the web search and the other one is Python interpreter. So given the question of what is
Apple's revenue in 2023, you just need one information to answer the question, which is
Apple 2023 revenue, and the LLM will have enough information to respond to the query. The Cohere
API also supports parallel tool calling, which we didn't see in the previous section. So now,
if the question is what is Apple's and Google's revenue in 2023, now the LLM needs two separate
information, the revenue of Apple and Google separately for it to be able to respond. And for
this, it needs to run queries in parallel. And then we get to the scenario of sequential
reasoning where the tool calls run in multiple steps. So for example, if you have a question
of plot Apple's 2023 revenue on a bar chart, you first need to get the Apple 2023 revenue
information, and then only you can use that information to run a Python function to plot
it on a chart. And the same way how you saw in single step, the Cohere API also supports
running multi-step in parallel. Okay, so now we are back to the code example,
and now we are using the same steps that we saw in the previous section. The only difference is
that we are now wrapping the whole four steps in a function. And the reason for that is we are
allowing for multi-step to happen. And in particular, here we have a loop of tool calls.
As long as the model continues to generate tool calls in every step, it will continue to run in
this loop of tool calling and getting the two results in steps two and three. And finally,
once the model decides that no more tool calls are required, it will continue to generate the
response. Okay, so this is an example that we're going to use. The question is, what's that feature
to view artifacts? Do you have any Jupyter notebook examples? So this requires the model to
first figure out what's that feature. And once it knows what that feature is, only then it will be
able to search for the code examples for that feature. So it requires two steps to respond to
this question. So now you can see that showing in the tool plan here. So it says that the model
will search for the feature to view artifacts and then search for Jupyter notebooks examples
of this feature. So that's an example of a model taking multiple steps to answer a question. So
let's extend that concept a little bit further. So multi-step scenario is useful for sequential
reasoning example that we saw earlier, but it's also useful when the model needs to make
adjustments and corrections based on the output that it receives from a particular step. The
model says that I will search for weave product from the developer docs and write an answer based
on that. It goes on to search the developer docs, but the problem we have here is that the developer
docs doesn't contain information about the weave product. So now the model says that I could not
find information about weave product. So it does a replanning and it will search the internet for
this information. Now it needs a second step to respond to the query. And now in the second step
is calling the internet with a similar query. It gets back the results. And now the internet
does contain more information about weave and because of that is able to generate the response.
Weave is the lightweight toolkit for tracking and evaluating LLM applications.