The tool use approach is especially useful
because it enables you to perform
RAG over structured data.
So we have looked at the search code example
tool briefly in the previous session,
but now we are formally introducing it.
So what we have here is we have a Python function
to query code examples.
But now instead of just querying based on textual information,
we have further information that we
can use to filter the examples that we want retrieved.
So the query itself, which is the string, now
we have the file type, programming language,
as well as the language.
So let's look at the first example
of using structured queries on the search code examples tool.
So the question here is any GPT notebook for data
visioning with artifacts.
And based on that, the model response
that is a GPT notebook for the model data
visioning with artifacts.
So for querying structured data, we'll
use an example of querying this CSV of mock evaluation results.
So in order to be able to query the CSV file,
we are going to leverage a langchain set of tools, which
is the Python interpreter.
And how we implement it is over here.
So we define a Python interpreter using line chain.
And here is how we're going to define it in the schema
that we provide to the model.
So here we give the name, analyze evaluation results,
and we give a description of generating Python code
using the pandas library to analyze
evaluation results from a data frame called
evaluation_results.
So now we have set up the tool schema for the model
to generate the right code to pass to the Python
interpreter.
So let's now see how it works with the code example.
So we have a question now, what's the average evaluation
score in run A?
So now the model decides that it needs
to use the analyze evaluation results tool.
It generates the pandas code, and it gets the answer
based on the code it generates.
So yeah, it's filtering the data frame for run A,
calculating the average score over here,
and printing the results.
So 0.63 is the correct answer.
We'll try with a few more examples.
Again, it decides to use the same tool,
generating the pandas code, and then giving the answer.
And as you notice, again, it generates the citations
based on the result that it gets from the two results
that it gets from the Python interpreter.
And this sample is 4.8 seconds, which is also the correct answer
that we are looking for.
Let's try a bit more complex example.
Which use case uses the least amount of tokens on average?
Show the comparison in the markdown table.
So now it will again use the same tool,
generate the two calls, and then giving the response
in the markdown table.
And now we look at the final example
of using the Python interpreter to create plots.
And here it generates the evaluation score
by temperature for extract names, use case for each
of the temperature settings.
And that concludes the section on agentic RAG with tool use.