So in this section, we'll get the first introduction to tool use by looking at the
tool use workflow with a few specific examples. So in a nutshell, tool use workflow works in four
steps. You have four different components. The first is the user, the application that the user
is interacting with. In our case, we'll be using Jupyter notebook as the app. We also have the LLM
as the engine to run all the different parts of tool calling and response generation. And you also
have the tools themselves. So the first step in the workflow is to first get the user message.
And using this user message, the second step is for the LLM to generate the tool calls
to the tools that it's given to. And then step three is for the application to execute the tool
calling and to get back the two results and sending it back to the LLM. And finally, for the
LLM to use these results to generate response with citations. So note that steps two and three can
run multiple times before the response is generated. For example, in complex scenarios
where the model will need to look for information in multiple sequences. So this is where the Cohere
API helps you by supporting this out of the box. So with the Cohere API, you also get citations
from tool use. The same way that you get citations from using the chat API for RAG, you also get that
with tool use and citations make responses verifiable. And we'll see how it works in the
Cohere example. So here we are importing the necessary libraries and that also includes
the two definitions that we have defined in the previous section, as well as defining the Cohere
client, which we are using the version 2 client in this example. So we are also defining the
functions map variable here for us to use in the function call later as a helper function.
We are also defining a system message, which tells a bit more information to the LLM to help it
go through and run its tasks. So you are in system helps developers use ways and biases
and so on. So you are equipped with a number of tools that can provide different types of
information and yeah, just giving a bit more information to the LLM on the kind of task that
is expected to do. So now going back to the slide that we showed you now, this is the first step of
getting the user message. In this case, we'll try a few examples where we can refine the output of
a run being the first one. And here we are pending and building the chat history through the messages
variable, first with a system message and then pending with the user message. And this chat
history will be required for the LLM as it goes along with the tool calling and generating the
response so that it has all the context it needs to perform a task. And step two, the model will
generate tool calls if it determines that it requires any. So what happens here is that we
are calling the chat endpoint, giving the model parameter as command R+, which is what we're going
to use. The messages, which is the chat history that we have defined earlier. Tools, so this is
the list of tool schemas that we have defined in the previous section as well as the temperature
in this case, we are giving it 0.3. And the response contains a few, a couple of important
information. So the first is tool plan. So here the model will describe the plan it will do given
the user query. So the next step is to execute the tools, which is done by calling the developer docs.
And if you recall, we are, we having a predefined list of documents that we pass for any query,
just for simplicity. And this is done by the function variable that we had defined earlier
and passing back the result to this cohere tool content object and appending the required
information that you see here in terms of the tool call ID that's generated as well as the
content that we get back. So this is the tool as you could change step. And then we are now
in a position that the model has all the information that it needs to respond to the
user message. Now that it has performed the tool calls and received the results back. So it takes
the messages that is now updated with the tool calls and tool results and uses it to generate
the response. And here it says that to view the output of run navigate to the app UI, select
relevant project and choose run from the runs table. So you can further verify the response by
printing the citation. So you have another object in the message response. So here you can see that
it generates fine grained citations, which contains the start and end points of specific
text spans where it uses external documents to ground its response. And to make it simpler,
you can see all the citations here, which are now printed in a more simpler way. So you have
all the start and end points, and you have the exact text where it cites from the source and also
the sources themselves.