Hi, my name is Meor. In this section, we'll be talking about the agentic approach of
performing RAG and specifically we'll be using the tool use capabilities of the Cohere API.
In this first section, we'll talk about the transition from RAG to tool use approach.
RAG gives LLMs the capability to ground their responses in external text data.
So tool use takes the RAG concept to the next level. It gives the flexibility and robustness
to a RAG system. Whereas a typical RAG system only have access on a vector store, for example,
that stores unstructured data that are retrieved through the embeddings. With tool use, you can
access any kind of tool that can give you information given a type of query that you give them.
So it can be a web search tool, it can be a Python interpreter tool, it can be structured data, it can
be any API that you can interact with that you can send and get information back. So instead of
retrieving information from unstructured documents in simple RAG, we can do that from any source tool
use. So tool use generalizes the concept of RAG and whereas the concept in general is still the
same, if you look at these two diagrams, it's still sending, getting a message, retrieving
something and giving a response. With tool use, you can do this with a much broader set of tools
and much more, in much more flexible way. So this makes an LLM more connected to the external world,
can take a broader range of actions and is more flexible overall.