Let's look at some of the challenges you might face
when implementing data ingestion pipelines.
Again, we'll draw upon our experience with wandbot.
In our journey with wandbot,
we encountered several pitfalls.
First, we struggled with incorrect data parsing
and had trouble with parsing the documentation
and code snippets using out-of-the-box parsers.
We also faced format discrepancies.
Different parts of our dataset used different formats
which led to inconsistencies in our parse data.
Chunking was another challenge.
Initially, our chunks were somewhat incoherent,
breaking apart related information.
This affected the quality of our responses.
And of course, we had to deal with the issue
of outdated knowledge.
In a fast-moving field like ours,
information can become obsolete really quickly.
So how did we address these issues?
We developed a tailored parsing approach
that could handle our specific documentation structure
and code formats.
We implemented a systematic evaluation
of our chunking strategy,
continuously testing and refining our approach.
We also adopted a staged approach to evaluation.
Instead of trying to fix everything at once,
we tackled issues in manageable groups,
running evaluations on major groups of commits.
This process wasn't quick or easy,
but it led to significant improvements overall.
It's important to note that troubleshooting
ingestion issues is an ongoing process.
It requires patience, systematic evaluation,
and a willingness to continuously refine your approach.