Hello everyone and welcome to the third hands-on session of our RAG course.
In this chapter, we'll dive into data ingestion and pre-processing. We'll focus on tokenization,
chunking, and explore a few different retrieval methods and compare and evaluate their impact
on our RAG pipeline. So let's get started. After going through the same initial setup steps and
fetching our raw data set using Weave, we start with revisiting tokenization. In chapter one,
we naively tokenized our data set into words. But it's often good practice to tokenize our data set
using the same tokenizer as the model we intend to use. Here, we're using Cohere's tokenizer to
accurately count tokens in our documents. It's crucial for our RAG system as it helps us manage
context windows and estimate the computational costs of our system. Notice how we update our
raw data with accurate token counts. This often differs significantly from simple word counts,
highlighting the importance of proper tokenization in RAG pipelines. Next, we pre-process our data by
removing markdown elements and special characters. Here, we specifically focus on two main functions.
The convert contents to text function. This function converts raw markdown to HTML and then
uses beautiful soup to remove image links, images, and other formatting information. Then, we have the
make text tokenization save function. This function removes any special tokens present in the text,
special characters here are those defined in the tokenizer and may vary depending on the model used.
This cleaning step is vital for sanitizing our input and improving the retrieval accuracy.
Again, we publish our pre-processed data set to V for easy tracking and reproducibility.