Having understood the pillars of data ingestion, let's dive into the practical side of things.
Preparing your data for RAG.
This process is crucial because it's the bridge between your data and a high-performing RAG system.
Let's break down the key steps.
First, we clean and extract the data.
This is like sorting through a messy closet.
We keep what we need and toss out what we don't.
Next, we convert everything into plain text.
Think of this as translating everything into a common language for our LLM.
Then comes segmentation.
We break our text into smaller, manageable pieces.
After that, we create vector representations.
This is where we translate our text into numerical data that our retrieval system can process efficiently.
Finally, we store everything in a vector database.
This is our organized, easily searchable library of information.
Each of these steps plays a crucial role in setting up your RAG system for success.
They ensure that when your system needs to retrieve and generate information,
it can do so quickly and accurately.
Let's examine data parsing a little more.
It plays a crucial role in converting raw data into a format our RAG system can work with.
First, let's look at some tools you might encounter in the wild.
You've got options like unstructured, firecrawl, multi-on,
textract, and Azure Document Intelligence.
These are great off-the-shelf solutions that can handle a wide variety of document types.
However, it's important to understand that sometimes a more tailored approach is necessary.
To illustrate this, let's look at our approach with wandbot.
In our case, we deal with some pretty specific document types.
So, we've taken a more tailored approach.
For our Markdown documents, we've built a custom parser that preserves the structure
and context of the text.
When it comes to Jupyter notebooks, we use nbconvert to convert them into Markdown
and then parse them with our custom parser.
And for code analysis, we use concrete syntax trees
to preserve and extract the syntax and structure of the code.
The key takeaway here is that while there are many great tools out there,
many a time you need a custom solution to really nail your specific use case.
It's all about finding the right balance between off-the-shelf convenience and tailored efficiency.