Hello and welcome to chapter 3 of our course.
In this chapter, we'll dive into a crucial aspect of RAG systems,
data ingestion and pre-processing.
Think of this chapter as your guidebook to transform your raw data
into the fuel that powers your RAG engine.
We'll explore how to process and convert all sorts of information
from documents to code snippets into a format
that your RAG system can work with efficiently.
Let's take a look at what we're going to cover in this chapter.
First, we're going to really dig into what data ingestion means for RAG systems.
We'll then explore some techniques for formatting your data.
Next, we're going to dive into the art of chunking.
We'll also look at how to use metadata to give your system even more context.
Finally, you'll learn how to spot and fix common ingestion issues.
By the end of this chapter, you'll have a solid grasp
of how to prepare your data for optimal RAG performance.
This is the foundation that can really take your RAG system to the next level.
So let's dive in.