Let's talk a little bit about metadata in RAG.
Metadata is essentially data about your data.
It's like the nutritional information on a food package.
It gives you the important details without you having to analyze the entire contents of the package.
In RAG systems, we typically work with two types of metadata.
There is document metadata, which is information about the entire document,
such as title, source, and maybe even a brief summary of the document.
On the other hand, there is chunk metadata,
and this is more granular, providing context for specific segments of the text.
But how do we actually extract and enhance our documents with metadata?
Here are a few techniques we can use from traditional natural language processing.
We can use entity extraction to identify and classify named entities in the text.
We can also use classification to categorize the content and generate new tags for the text.
And relationship extraction takes these a step further
and helps identify how different entities in the text relate to each other.
These are just a few techniques to enrich our content with metadata.
By leveraging metadata effectively, a RAG system can understand
and not just what the content says, but what it's about
and how different pieces of information relate to each other.
Now let's see how metadata works in practice by looking at our approach with wandbot.
Our metadata strategy is twofold.
First, we focus on document-level metadata.
This includes the source of the document.
For instance, is it from our official docs, our GitHub repo, or our blog post?
The type of document, things like, is it API documentation, a tutorial, or a conceptual guide?
The language that the document is written in.
This is crucial for multilingual support.
Then we dive into more granular, chunk-level metadata.
We capture structural information here.
For instance, is the chunk a header, a code block, or a paragraph?
For code chunks, we note the programming language used.
We also tag version-specific information, which is crucial for providing accurate and up-to-date responses.
For instance, if a user asks about a specific pattern function,
our metadata helps us quickly narrow down the relevant code chunks,
ensuring we provide the most accurate and contextually appropriate response.
Remember, a well-thought-out metadata strategy can significantly enhance your RAG system's ability
to provide relevant and accurate responses.
It's about adding those extra layers of context that helps your system understand not just the content,
but its relevance and applicability.