In chapter 1, we saw how to use tf-idf vectors to build a basic retriever.
Here, we'll explore another type of retrieval method called best matching 25 or bm25 in short.
bm25 is an evolution of tf-idf that better handles document length and term frequency saturation
using a probabilistic approach. By implementing both methods and ingesting data into the two
retrievers, we can more effectively compare their impact on our RAG pipeline. Having ingested the
data into the retrievers, we can finally use Weave to evaluate them holistically. This allows us to
compare their retrieval performance as well as the overall impact on the RAG pipeline. After running
the evaluations, you should be able to compare the performance of the two methods in your Weave
dashboard. Here, you'll notice that the bm25 retriever generally performs better than the
tf-idf retriever on most metrics.