Hello, my name is Ayush and I will be your instructor for this chapter focused on evaluating
LLM applications. We will build from where Bharat left off in the last chapter.
Before we start, a crucial disclaimer. Every application is unique, so we designed this
chapter to help build a mental model of approaching evaluation. In this chapter, we will explore
the importance of evaluating LLM applications. We will dive into practical approaches and
cover a few strategies. We will explore ideas to build eval datasets and finally try to
drill the idea of evaluation-driven development.
Talking about evaluation-driven development, we learned it the hard way. A few months ago,
we refactored wandbot to make it faster and better. In a rush to get it done quickly,
in two weeks time, we skipped through evaluating major changes. Well, our first evaluation
of the refactored branch gave only 9% accuracy, which was a significant drop from our baseline
of 72%. We made a mistake, so you don't have to. In order to do it right, we created
a GitHub branch, cherry-picked the changes and evaluated each one. After running 50 evaluations
and spending $2000 over a span of another 6 weeks, we identified the key issues, resolved
them and ultimately improved the accuracy by 8% over the baseline.