We will now see an LLM Evaluator in action. For our use case, we care about the correctness,
relevancy and faithfulness of the generative response. The correctness metric compares
the response to the ground truth. The relevancy metric checks if the response is relevant
to the user query, while the faithfulness measures the factual consistency of the response
given retrieved context.
In this colab, we have only implemented the correctness metric. We leave the other two
metrics as an assignment for our viewers.
We set up our evaluation and evaluate our RAG pipeline like we have been doing. Now
let's go through the Weave dashboard to look through and dig deeper into the evaluation
result from this evaluation run.
If you have noticed, for this particular evaluation, we got a score of 0%. Why is that the case?
First, let's look into the system prompt to understand what are the set of instructions
that we have provided and what's the scoring criteria and then we will look through few
of the examples to understand why the judge gave the score it gave.
Well, it's very easy because of this trace timeline to look through the judge's system
prompt. Because we are using Cohere, the underlying cohere.async, client v2 chat method
is the one responsible for making the API call. You can look through the system prompt
here. It clearly outlines the amount of information that is provided, what are the different instructions
or the criteria for evaluation and the evaluation range. So a 0 score is incorrect and does
not satisfy the criteria that is outlined here. Whereas a score of 2 is correct and
thoroughly answers the question. Remember that we are asking the LLM judge to return
a suggestion with the reason for why it believes the score, what is the final score, which
is 0 or 1 or 2 and the decision. Remember that the decision here is that if the score
is 2, only then the generative response is correct, otherwise it is not correct.
Now let's look for the score for this particular example. It gave a score of 0 and let's see
why. The generative answer provides code snippets for saving data to a wandb table but does
not address the specific user question about logging the outputs and the parameters. It
gave a score, it compared the ground truth with the response and came up with this reasoning.
Let's look at some other query. In this query for example, the question was, my distributed
runs are not in sync when using PyTorch Lightning integration, how do I fix that? And this is
the output that the system gave. Well, it gave a score of 1. It says that the generative
answer provides a code snippet to address the issue but does not cover all the relevant
point mentioned in the reference answer. So it's comparing against the reference answer,
such as proper logging setup, configuring the trainer and avoiding direct access to
one data front. So these are the things that are missing in the reference evaluation ground
truth and does it give us decision of incorrect. Like this, we can go through the entire sample
of 20 or so dataset and see where it failed and why it failed. And this will help us gain
more insight. What's more interesting is that for a given response, if I feel that
the LLM judge gave a score which is incorrect, I can maybe go and give it a feedback of thumbs
down and then I can write a piece of code and pull down all the traces or all the evaluation
runs where I have given a particular kind of emoji indicating a particular kind of intent.
In this case, a thumbs down is intending that the LLM response or the LLM judgment
is not in line with my own judgment of the generative response. And this information
or this data can help me figure out what kind of future examples I would like to give in
the system prompt to align the judge with the human judgment as well as what kind of
tweaking I should do with the system prompt to again align the LLM judge with my own judgment.
And this is an exercise that we have done for wandbot and we'll show some flavor of this.