Well, LLM evaluators have limitations as well, but there are some solutions.
The evaluator is non-deterministic, thus ideally we should be running 3-5 trials per experiment.
You might have already thought about it if we are using an LLM to evaluate an LLM system
who evaluates the evaluator. Remember the concept of alignment where we align the evaluator's
judgement with that of human judgement with careful prompting.
Cost is obviously higher compared to traditional metrics, but remember you are using LLM evaluator
to measure abstract concepts and manual evaluation will be very costly and time consuming.
Finally, the evaluation dataset needs to be updated if the data source has changed, thus
requiring a careful inspection of the evaluator's alignment with human judgement. In my opinion,
having a dedicated team for evaluation makes a huge difference.