What's even more exciting is that because our simple RAG pipeline is written using Weave.model
or in a structured manner, we can easily switch the underlying LLM from Command R to Command R+, re-initialize
the RAG pipeline and run the evaluation on all the metrics that we have discussed so
far.
Using the Weave dashboard, we can easily compare two evaluations.
In this case, I am comparing the evaluation of two RAG pipeline, one using Command R and another
one using Command R+.
Click on the compare button and we have the comparison dashboard created for us automatically.
We can look through the differences or the delta of the metrics that changed and the
best part is that we can look through individual samples and compare the answer for all of
these.
For example, here this particular output got a score of 1, whereas this output only got
a score of 0.
Maybe there was something wrong when Command R was used and we can literally run through
all the 20 samples here and try to figure out where our system is failing.
This concludes how we can use evaluation on Weave for evaluation driven development to
improve the quality of our RAG pipeline.