In the last chapter, we created a simple RAG pipeline.
However, RAG is as good as the quality of the retrieval system, the quality of the generated
response, and the quality of LLM to follow instructions.
Depending on the complexity of your application, you should consider measuring the quality
of each component.
Talking about components, we start off by evaluating a response by comparing it against
ground truth.
This is called end-to-end evaluation or system evaluation.
We do this because response is non-deterministic in nature.
We must also evaluate other non-deterministic components of our pipeline like the retrieval
system.
We can evaluate the context by ranking it against ground truth context or even ask an
LLM to judge if the generated response is based on the retrieved context.
This is called component evaluation.
So far, we have focused on evaluation using ground truth.
But the need for ground truth depends on what we want to evaluate, which can further be
bucketed into three categories.
We can compare evaluation measures, aspects like toxicity, racial bias, or whether a response
is grounded on source text.
Pairwise evaluation compares two or more responses to the same query measuring factors like tone
or coherence.
Both these evaluations can be done without ground truth.
Finally, if we have or can create a gold standard reference, we can perform reference evaluation
typically used to measure the structure of a response or its inclusion of specific information.
Now let's talk about evaluation in practice.
Practically, your evaluation journey begins while building your system.
You eyeball the response of the system to see if it is decent.
This is the quickest way of evaluation but is less reliable because you will not be covering
every edge case.
You can then consider hiring annotators to manually evaluate your system.
While building wandbot eval set, in-house MLEs acted as the domain expert annotators.
This is both expensive and time consuming but most reliable.
Somewhere in between the two spectrums, we have a concept of LLM as a judge.
That is, we use an equally powerful LLM to score our system or components of our system.
Talking about evaluation dataset, it is meaningful as long as it is highly correlated with your
production distribution.
Same goes for the choice of your metric.
It needs to be correlated with your use case.
Public benchmarks do not correlate on both the axes while human evaluation or user testing
are moderate to highly correlated but are slow and expensive for rapid iteration cycles.
The idea is to build a small evaluation dataset, leverage LLM judges to evaluate components
of the system and via alignment, push this mode of evaluation to the top right quadrant.
That's mouthful.
We will go through it one by one.