But hey, before we do any fancy evaluation, let's take a step back from LLM as a judge
jargon and try to express the desired output in plain code. This is direct evaluation using
heuristics. The heuristics should form the first layer of your system evaluation. We
can use these metrics to inspect the structure of the response. Some examples can be to check
if there are bullet points or code snippets in the response. We can also check if the
response is of a certain length or is a valid JSON in case of structured output. Doing these
types of heuristics based evaluation will reinforce what we expect and hence make the
system more robust.
Writing assertions or unit tests are application specific. A more generic evaluation strategy
is to do reference-based evaluation using traditional metrics, like comparing the similarity
ratio between the normalized model output and the expected answer, or computing the
Laue distance. We are also showing both ROUGE and BLEU metrics. We again set up our evaluation
using Weave Evaluation, but this time we evaluate a simple RAG pipeline.