Now let's evaluate our retriever using an LLM evaluator. We will talk more formally about
this concept when we will evaluate a response generator. But here let me show you an LLM
evaluator in action for evaluating a component of the RAG pipeline. The idea is to first ask an LLM
to score each retrieved context based on a relevance to a given question. You can check
out the system prompt. The instruction is documented here which is to rank documents
based on their relevance to a given question as well as answer pair. The instructions are also
followed by a rubric or the scoring criteria. Here the criteria is to give a score in a range of 0 to
2 where 0 represents that the document is irrelevant whereas 1 is neutral and 2 is that
the document is highly relevant to the question answer pair. The final output of the judge should
look something like this where each context id is given a relevant score.
Based on this scoring by LLM we can then compute two metrics the mean relevance as well as the
rank score. The rank metric measures the position of the relevant chunks. We then set up our
evaluation like we did in the past and run the evaluation using our LLM as a judge metric.