The fundamental idea of evaluating a retriever is to know how well the retrieved content
matches the expected contents. One way of doing so is to rank the retrieved context against
Ground-Truth Context aka Reference Evaluation. Another way is to ask another LLM to judge if
the retrieved context is relevant for the user query aka Direct Evaluation. In most cases,
Reference Evaluation will give a more confident measure of the quality of your retriever.
A quick way of generating Ground-Truth Context is to first create clusters of semantically similar
chunks. You can then sample similar chunks and ask an LLM to come up with one or more queries
that can only be answered based on this information. At its core, retrieval evaluation is a search
problem. Thus, it is easiest to start with traditional information retrieval metrics.
Some ranking-based metrics are Hit Rate, which measures if there is at least one relevant
recommendation. Min-reciprocal ranking or MRR calculates the average of the reciprocal ranks
of the first relevant content. Normalized discounted cumulative gain or NDCG considers
both the relevance and the position of the items in the rank list. Together, they help measure
retriever's ability to pick context based on their relevance to the user or query.
The position of relevant context is important for the LLM to give proper attention or attribution to
it aka loss in the middle problem, which we will cover later in this chapter. We can also use
predictive quality metrics that measure if the retriever can make accurate predictions about
item relevance. Precision, recall, map, F1 score are familiar metrics in this category.
Now let's evaluate our TFIDF retriever from chapter 1 using these metrics.
Now let's evaluate our retriever using the metrics we have discussed so far.
We first download the chunk data from chapter 1.
We will import the TFIDF retriever, which is an instance of weave.model, and index the chunk data.
All the metrics we have discussed so far are implemented in the script
slash retriever underscore metrics dot py file. I would highly recommend you all to check this
file out. Note that every scoring function here has the same signature wherein it expects two
arguments model output, which is the list of retrieved contexts as well as context,
which is which are the ground truth context. Each metric is also decorated with weave.op.
Now that we have our evaluation data set, as well as the list of scoring functions,
we can set up our evaluation pipeline using Weave evaluation.
We then run the evaluation of our retriever using this pipeline.
Once the evaluation is done, we get a summary scores like this. Note that for each metric,
we have the mean score computed for us automatically.
Alternatively, we can go to the evaluation section of our Weave dashboard.
Here we find all the evaluation runs and we can even filter out runs based on the columns.
Clicking on the evaluation we just ran, we can check out the mean of each metrics.
We can also check out the scores on per sample basis.
We can choose to drill down further by checking out the trace timeline for our evaluation run.