Now let's head over to the Collab notebook for chapter 2, where we will be evaluating
the two main components of the RAG pipeline, the Retriever as well as the Response Generator.
We start off by setting up the required packages for this Collab notebook.
In this chapter we will be using wandb Weave for our evaluation purposes, but I've already
covered what wandb Weave is.
In this chapter we will focus on Weave Evaluation, which is a lightweight class that can be used
to evaluate the performance of a Weave model on a Weave dataset.
We first initialize a Weave client, which can track both the traces as well as the evaluation
scores.
Weave Evaluation begins by first building the evaluation set.
In our case, we used a subset of the evaluation dataset we had created for wandbot.
If you are interested, I would highly recommend checking out our series on how to evaluate
LLM, specifically part 1 as well as part 2.
The main takeaway from these reports are that we first deployed wandbot for internal usage
based on rigorous eyeballing-based evaluation.
We then analyzed the query distribution.
We sampled a good representative from the clusters we created to create a gold standard
set of queries.
We then used in-house MLEs to perform manual evaluation using Argila.
Remember that creating such evaluation platforms are easy these days.
To summarize, speed is key.
Use whatever means you have to create a meaningful eval set.
The evaluation samples are logged as Weave dataset.
You can check out the question, answer, and context triplets.
We can also drill down to individual questions, the ground truth answer, as well as the context
that was used to create this ground truth answer.
Obviously, while experimenting with your evaluation dataset, you will be creating multiple versions
of the evaluation set.
It's important that we keep track of the different versions.
For example, this version 4 had 20 examples, whereas the version 3 of the evaluation set
had only two examples.
This is how you keep iterating on eval set and keep building better and better quality
of the eval set.