The traditional metrics for evaluating generation fall short on measuring the semantics deeply
and usually ignore the contextual relevance of the user query.
It usually performs fuzzy exact match which are hard to interpret.
Furthermore, most track pipelines are nuanced and subjective demanding for better evaluation
metrics. Note however that these traditional metrics can be included in the evaluation suite
because of its speed. LLM evaluators can help overcome some of these limitations
but has its own set of problems. We have already used LLM as a judge to evaluate our retriever
but let us define what it means more formally here. The idea of LLM evaluator is based on two
facts. One, a powerful LLM can compare pieces of text and second it can follow instructions.
Using these two facts we can give a powerful LLM pieces of text like the retrieve context,
the generated response and the user query. We also give it a set of instructions which outline
the scoring criteria. The LLM then gives a score based on the learned internal representations.
One can pause here and ask two important questions. Are these scores deterministic
to which I would say a no. If we are using an LLM to evaluate an LLM system,
how can we evaluate the LLM evaluator in the first place. Well, we will get to it later.