Let's look at data ingestion and how we can speed it up and make it more efficient.
A general rule of thumb is to use multi-processing for your data ingestion operations,
like converting raw files to text or chunking them.
Depending on your use case, you can also approach indexing in multiple ways.
If you only have a few thousand samples, doing flat indexing is not a bad option.
You can also consider various variants of hierarchical indexing
to speed up searching through most relevant pieces of information.
Make sure your files, be it PDF, web pages or markdown are converted to a simple text
and associated metadata. This makes the whole application more efficient.
I like LlamaIndex's Document class which is an excellent abstraction for handling data.
Make sure you have validation in place which is very important.
Also ensure to keep track of your data versions with Weave dataset.
Baking in versioning tool like Weave is a one-time work but you get the benefits out of it
throughout the lifecycle of the project.