Selecting the right vector store is also very important.
Usually the likes of Chroma and Weaviate are all you need.
In wandbot, when we switched from FAISS to Chroma,
we got a massive speed boost.
This was mostly coming from the fact
that we were able to do efficient metadata filtering.
Note that for most applications,
fancy vector store is not necessary.
Vector stores are usually fast,
and super fast vector stores gain their speed
at the cost of recall.
For most applications like RAG, recall is more important.
For wandbot, we used in-memory vector store
to lower latency,
but note that this was only possible
because the total size of the documents to index
wasn't that huge.
And many applications will fall in this bracket.
However, using dedicated cloud managed DBs
make the application overall easy to manage
and easy to configure.