Let's start by talking about frameworks.
In general, be happy to use whatever suits your purpose,
but avoid framework overload.
While building wandbot, we switched from LlamaIndex to Instructor to LangChain or a mix of them.
It was an exercise to see what works well, but honestly, they are all great.
If your workflow is data heavy, consider using LlamaIndex.
And if it is LLM Paul heavy, consider using LangChain.
I highly recommend evaluating frameworks for yourself.
I'm also an active believer of using less abstractions wherever possible.
For wandbot, we use frameworks for generic tasks,
but wrote custom pure Pythonic code for performance-critical sections.
Finally, this is obvious, but asynchronous programming is your best friend.
Don't shy away from it.
Depending on use case, there can be multiple IO Bottlenecks,
and async programming can help.