LLM calls take the most time in a RAG pipeline.
If you're using an open source model, there are ways to speed up generation,
but most frontier LLM providers are already employing these tricks.
So the way ahead to reduce overhead due to LLM calls
is to make it parallel wherever possible.
Most frontier LLM providers can handle multiple requests
and this helps in parallelization.
Language expression language (LECL) is something we have used in wandbot
and something we recommend to parallelize LLM calls
while making the code more readable and efficient.
LECL allows to chain small components both sequentially and parallelly
and the best part is you can switch between sync and async mode
without changing anything in the code.
It just works.
Finally, try to batch user queries wherever possible.