Talking about configurability, if you are experimenting a lot with different LLM providers,
using LiteLLM's unified API is a good approach.
I, however, am also in favor of using the target LLM's SDK
if you aren't sure on what LLM you are going to be using.
Talking about system prompt, it can live directly in the script where it is going to be consumed
for a less complex code base, but we recommend using text files or JSON files to keep track
of the system prompts for more complex code bases.
Following good software principles is the best way ahead and make sure to evaluate everything possible.
Write unit tests, create LLM judges and everything else that we have covered in the chapters so far.
Something like wandb Weave can be really useful to keep track and version control everything,
be it code, the LLM, the prompts, etc.
It is a lightweight package and it doesn't take up a lot of code real estate.
Consider using it.
Finally, caching is something we recommend if you are handling a many requests at the same time.
The general idea is to cache pairs of input and output,
especially your LLM generated response for a given query.
During query time, if a new query matches some condition to an already existing cached query,
serve the cached response instead of generating a response.
This will massively speed up your application.
Well, this is the end of this short chapter.
I hope you learned something new and useful.
To conclude, here are some of the key takeaway pointers.
You should follow good software development practices to develop efficient applications.
Doing it right will give insights to improve and debug your application as well.
There is no need to stress about frameworks and make sure to evaluate everything you do.
Evaluation driven development is the best approach.
Finally, most tricks are use case dependent.
We have documented our wandbot refactoring journey,
which reduced the latency by 84% in this report.
I would highly recommend you all check this out.