Hi everyone, I'm Charles from Weaviate and today we're going to be covering how to set up Weaviate for your RAG application
and how to ingest your data into Weaviate.
And after that we're going to be learning how to query Weaviate for hybrid search
and using re-ranking to improve the quality of your results.
In this section we're going to be covering querying Weaviate and hybrid search.
So vector search is extremely powerful at capturing the semantic relationships between a query
and the documents you have stored in your database.
However sometimes we also want to add some of the precision of a traditional keyword search
which retrieves documents based on exact matches with your input queries.
Hybrid search is the answer for these scenarios and as such it's a critical component for building RAG applications.
By conducting a hybrid search we can ensure that our system is still able to retrieve documents
that may use very specific terms for fields such as medicine including medical names, anatomical terms
that otherwise might be lost with a pure vector search where the embedding model
might not be able to accurately represent certain domains.
So under the hood in Weaviate when you conduct a hybrid search
Weaviate conducts both a vector and keyword search in parallel.
The results of both of these searches are then merged and ranked accordingly to a weighted system.
The degree to which your search favors or keyword or vector results can be manually adjusted with the alpha parameter.
Tuning this parameter balances precision and recall.
So how do we understand the alpha parameter?
Well in Weaviate an alpha parameter of zero would result in a pure BM25 search over your documents.
An alpha parameter of one would result in a pure vector search over your documents
and an alpha parameter of 0.5 would give you a balanced 50-50 blend of results between BM25 and vector search.
Also in this section we're going to be covering re-ranking using Cohere's re-ranking API.
We will re-rank our results to ensure that we get the best possible results for more difficult questions.
So let's dive in.
To begin with before we do a hybrid search I'm going to show this query using a pure vector search.
With Weaviate Client a pure vector search can be conducted using the near vector method
or in our case because we already configured the vectorizer for collection the near text method.
So firstly let's just do a direct vector search.
So the question here is how to get started using Weave.
Well if we actually look at the result here we can see it's kind of right.
It's brought us to a page which gives us an introduction for Weave
but really what I'm looking for here is how to actually get started using Weave in my code.
So for that we're going to switch over to a hybrid search
and all you need to do to conduct a hybrid search is do collection.query.hybrid.
You pass in your query, you pass in your limit which is how many results you want
and then you also just pass in your alpha parameter.
So here we're going to put in an alpha parameter of 0.5
meaning we want a balance between BM25 and pure vector search.
So let's run that exact same query again.
Well now the results are actually showing more what I was looking for
which is an actual code setup of how to get started using Weave in your project.
So here we can see that the addition of BM25 has actually really brought in results that
kind of really emphasize how to get started because that's what this document mentions.
So finally we're going to use a re-ranker to help answer more complex questions.
So here we have a query, how do I set up a sweep to run on multiple GPU-enabled machines at the same time?
So this is a more complex query.
So let's see how it performs firstly just with the hybrid search that we conducted in the last section.
So I've just brought that query in and the result we get isn't quite what I was looking for.
It's actually bringing back pages from a tutorial on how to set up minikube with GPUs
whereas that's not really what we're looking for in this section.
However if I go down here and now rerun the same question using the Cohere re-ranker
which we simply call by passing a re-rank parameter into our hybrid query.
If we run that now, let's have a look at the page it brought back.
So it brought back guides, sweep, parallelize agents.
That's what we were looking for.
This is a page that describes how to do a parallel sweep using wandb agents on multiple GPUs.
And this really shows the power of re-rankers in these types of situations because
they can really focus on all the data we brought back compared to the query and
kind of recontextualize and reorder the documents according to the query that we had.
So that's it for how to set up Weaviate for your rag applications.
So in this you should now know how to import your data objects into Weaviate,
how to set up vectorizers and re-rankers for your collection,
and finally how to conduct hybrid searches and then how to re-rank those results using a re-ranker.
Thanks.