Hi everyone, I'm Charles from Weaviate and in this section I'm going to be covering how to build
production-ready RAG applications with Weaviate back to database, as well as how to optimize your
search and increase the quality using our built-in hybrid search functionality. And finally we're
going to cover how to use Cohere's re-ranker to improve the final quality of your results using
Weaviate. As your use case expands from a POC stage to a fully fledged application, the question
of how to make it ready for production scale will likely come to mind. Weaviate is designed to
optimize the storage and querying of unstructured data to allow fast and efficient retrieval of
similar objects and most importantly it enables users to quickly build AI native applications
with a rich ecosystem of tooling and services. So let's jump in. So here to begin with I've just
imported my Weaviate Python client as well as Weave which we'll be using to fetch the data set
from the pre-processed data set from the previous sections. We're using Weaviate Cloud to streamline
setting up Weaviate. This Weaviate Cloud is built on top of Weaviate's core open source database
and by using Weaviate Cloud for building our application we don't need to worry about hosting
or infrastructure setup, we get to just focus on building the application. So all I need for using
Weaviate Cloud is my Weaviate URL and my Weaviate key. So I'm going to set those here.
Oops. Set those here and I'm also going to fetch our pre-processed data
from Weave that we created in the last section.
So Weaviate also has a number of modules and integrations. One of them is Cohere and we provide
integrations for Cohere's embed, re-rank and chat APIs. When initializing our Weaviate client below
we simply add the Cohere API key in as an entry to our headers argument and we're ready to start
using any of the API integrations that we need. So I create our client here and that's it, that's
our Weaviate client created. So now we need to create a collection. So collections are where we
store objects and build vector indexes. To create a collection we need a unique property collection
and then we need a list of properties and their corresponding data types. Optionally we can add
additional configuration such as a vectorizer config and a re-ranker config which in this setup
we're going to use Cohere's APIs for. So once created the collection is ready to ingest and index data.
There's no need to pass vectors in manually. Our vectorizer will make all the calls to Cohere's
embed endpoint in the background. So here you can see I have a collection and I'm giving it this name
wandb weaviate demo. I've passed in a vectorizer config which is text-effect Cohere as well as a
re-ranker config which is Cohere's re-ranker. I've added four properties, parsed content, source, words
and parse tokens as well as the corresponding data type for each of those. So if I hit enter here
that should create the collection. So now it's time to import our data. Before we start querying
our data for the rag app we need to first get it into Weaviate. Weaviate provides an optimized batch
API that enables users to add multiple data objects to their collection without having to
worry about configuring batches themselves. By initializing a batch object and adding your
batches inside the context manager the client will dynamically add batches to your collection
and since we've already initialized our collection the default Cohere vectorizer
vectorizes these objects and they'll have their embeddings created during the import step.
So here you can see I'm just creating the batch object and I'm just adding
adding objects from our data set to that and those will all be added automatically. So let's run this.
And there we have it the objects are imported and we can double check that they've all been added by
doing the length of the collection and here we can see that there's 406 items which corresponds to
all the docs that we've added. So that's it that's how you can add set up a Weaviate client and
collection and add your data to it. It only takes a few short steps and we're now ready to start
querying.