In this course, we'll refer to wandbot quite often as a practical example of a RAG application.
So let me introduce you to wandbot and some of its applications.
wandbot is our LLM-powered document assistant, and it has been a total game changer for us.
First off, wandbot offers our free users support through chat and email.
This has been a huge boost to our customer service,
allowing us to provide instant help to users around the clock.
But it's not just our external users who are benefiting.
Our internal teams love wandbot.
It has made finding information from our docs a total breeze.
Building wandbot actually helped us improve our documentation.
As we developed the system, we gained new insights into how users interact with our docs,
allowing us to optimize and clarify our content.
Now, here's something I'm particularly excited about.
We built wandbot in the open. You can find it on GitHub right now.
We wanted to share our work with the community.
We hope that AI developers can use wandbot as a reference,
learn from our experience, and maybe even contribute to its development.
By exploring wandbot, you'll get a first-hand look at building an effective RAG system.
And by the end of this course, you will have the knowledge and skills to build something similar,
tailored to your own unique needs and use cases.
As we progress through the course,
we'll guide you through the process of building a developer assistant.
We'll draw upon our experience of having had wandbot in production for over 18 months.
What's interesting is how versatile RAG systems like wandbot can be.
We initially created it for a specific purpose, but it ended up doing so much more.
For instance, wandbot has made customer self-service incredibly easy.
Our support agents are using wandbot to provide faster and more accurate help.
And surprisingly, our developers are using it to quickly generate code snippets and API documentation.
As we walk through the process of building a RAG application
and explore the advanced techniques that make systems like wandbot so effective and adaptable,
you'll gain the skills to create RAG systems that meet a wide range of needs,
just like wandbot did for us.
You'll get the hands-on experience that you can apply to real-world scenarios
and develop robust and versatile RAG systems of your own.