Let's talk about a key principle in our development of wandbot, the 80-20 rule.
We found that about 80% of user queries can be resolved using just 20% of our available
information.
So how do we apply this to building our RAG system?
Here's our approach.
First, we prioritize high-impact content, focusing on the most critical 20% of our documentation.
We zero in on common queries, optimizing for the 20% that represents 80% of our users'
queries.
We believe in iterative improvement, tackling the most impactful problems first.
And we are always mindful of technical debt, balancing quick fixes with long-term maintainability.
Now some level of hallucination is unavoidable in LLM-based systems.
That's why we focus on addressing issues with the most frequent and impactful queries first.
Remember, the goal isn't perfection, it's excellence.
By focusing on what matters most, we can create a system that delivers outstanding results
for majority of use cases while continuously improving over time.
This approach has been key to wandbot's success, and it's a principle you can apply to your
own RAG projects to maximize impact and efficiency.
Balancing risks and rewards in AI-powered systems is a bit like walking a tightrope.
Our experience with wandbot has shown us that when done right, the payoff can be huge.
We rolled out wandbot in stages, starting small with free users on Discord and then expanding
to chat and email support.
This allowed us to get real feedback and fine-tune the system without too much pressure.
We tackled challenges like inaccurate responses by adding source citations and refreshing
our content regularly.
To address privacy concerns, we anonymized user data.
And to address the lack of human touch, we ensured that customers have a clear path to
get human help when needed.
Now let's talk about rewards.
We've seen significant improvements to user satisfaction.
People love instant and accurate answers to their questions.
Our support team's workload has decreased significantly.
And for our global users, it's like having a 24-7 Weights & Biases expert at their fingertips.
The bottom line is, wandbot has shown us that with careful planning and constant tweaking,
a RAG system can greatly enhance customer assistance and keep risks at a check.