Hello everyone and welcome to the first chapter of our course on retrieval augmented generation.
In this chapter, we'll set the stage for the rest of the course by introducing a few concepts,
challenges, and best practices in RAG systems. We'll also give you a sneak peek into wandbot,
our production RAG system that we'll use as a case study throughout this course.
Here's what you can expect to learn in this chapter. First, we'll explore the core components
that make up an advanced RAG system. Then, we'll discuss the challenges that you're likely to face
implementing a RAG system. Next, we'll then cover a few best practices that we've developed through
our experience with building wandbot. And finally, we'll put theory into practice by guiding you
through building a RAG system. This hands-on experience will serve as the foundation that
we'll build upon and refine through the rest of the course. By the end of this chapter,
you should have the necessary foundation required to start your journey into building an advanced
RAG system that we will explore in this course.