Let's start by revisiting the basics.
I know most of you taking this course are probably already familiar with the fundamental
RAG process, but here's a quick refresher anyway.
So in a nutshell, a simple RAG system has four main steps.
First, we've got the query.
This is where it all begins.
A user comes along with a question or a request.
We then dig through our knowledge base, looking for any information that might be relevant
to the user's query.
Next, we take a large language model and feed it two things.
The context we just retrieved and the user's original query.
The LLM then works its magic to craft a response.
And finally, we deliver the answer back to the user, hopefully solving their problem
or answering that question.
Now, this basic process is already quite powerful.
It combines the precision of a retrieval system with the flexibility of a large language model
to deliver a contextual response that drives value to our users.
Now that we've had a refresher on the basics of a RAG system, let's kick things up a notch.
In this course, we are going to transform that simple RAG system into something more
sophisticated.
You'll notice that we've added a few extra steps to the RAG process in this slide.
Let me walk you through what's new and why it matters.
Just like before, we start with the query.
But here, we've added an enhancement step to improve the initial query.
Doing this dramatically improves our chances of finding the right information.
Next, we still got the retrieval step, but look what comes after.
We've added a re-rank stage.
This is crucial.
It's not enough to just find the relevant information.
We need to make sure we're using the most useful information.
Then, we still have an LLM generate a response, but now we've added a validation stage.
This is our quality control, where we double check the generated responses, make sure it's
accurate, appropriate, and actually answers the user's question.
Finally, we deliver the answer back to the user.
Now, you might wonder, why go through all this trouble?
Well, these additional stages are what separates a good RAG system from a great one.
They help us handle more complex queries, provide more accurate and relevant responses,
and ultimately deliver a better user experience.
Of course, implementing these extra steps comes with its own challenges.
We'll discuss these challenges throughout the course, along with the strategies to overcome
them.