Building any successful application requires adherence to some best practices.
Our experience with wandbot has taught us a few key lessons,
and these lessons can be applied to any RAG system you are working on.
First, start with a clear use case and well-defined success metrics.
For wandbot, we focused on improving how users navigate our documentation,
setting specific goals to measure our progress.
Data quality is crucial.
We put a lot of effort into ensuring our documentation is comprehensive and up-to-date.
This high-quality foundation is what allows wandbot to provide accurate and relevant responses.
Next, we fully embraced evaluation-driven development.
This means constantly assessing wandbot's performance against predefined metrics
and allowing for iterative improvement.
Lastly, we developed a robust evaluation framework.
This isn't just about accuracy.
It's about looking at relevance, faithfulness, and a range of other factors.
This multidimensional approach helps us truly understand our system's performance.
These practices were essential in wandbot's development
and can significantly improve any RAG system you are working on.
In the next slide, we'll continue with a few more best practices
that have really made a difference for us.
Continuing with our best practices, let's look at a few more key principles.
While LLMs are powerful, we've learned that regular reviews by subject matter experts
are essential. They ensure responses remain accurate and relevant,
catching any quirks that might slip through automated checks.
We've also prioritized user experience and interface design.
It's about presenting information in a way that's easy to navigate and understand.
Transparency is another key factor.
We are always upfront about users interacting with a bot
and provide citations for wandbot's responses.
This builds trust and gives users the option to dig deeper if they want.
Lastly, we've embraced continuous improvement.
Our documentation isn't static and neither are user needs.
We're constantly updating wandbot to keep pace with these changes.
These practices, combined with the ones we discussed earlier,
form the backbone of wandbot's success.
They've helped us build a RAG system that not only performs well,
but also earns and maintains user trust.
Keep these principles in mind as you build your own RAG application.
They can make a real difference in your application's success.