Hello everyone and welcome to the first hands-on session of this course. In this session, we'll
build a simple rag application over the weights and biases documentation. We start off by doing
some initial setup and downloading our data set using weights and biases artifact. We've already
set up most of the files for this data set so you should be able to run and get started very quickly.
You will notice that most of these documents are in Markdown format and we're going to convert
these documents into a list of dictionaries with some content and metadata. Metadata is usually
some extra information about our documents and in this case we are just storing the source of
the document and the number of tokens that is present in each document. Our data set contains
about 260,000 tokens which is a good candidate for building a simple rag system. It's a good time
to talk about weights and biases Weave. Weights and biases Weave is a lightweight toolkit for
tracking and evaluating LLM applications and since we are building a rag application,
this might be a good time to plug in weave. It helps us log and debug large language model inputs
and outputs and trace their calls and also provides nice versioning of data sets and models.
In this case, we're going to take our raw data set and put it into a weights and biases weave data set
and then you know publish it so that we can version it and track it for future purposes.
Next, we proceed with chunking our data. Chunking is usually important because you know most
embedding models have a limit of about 512 tokens and we are also using it to like you know reduce
the number of tokens that we send to our large language model. In this case, we'll be doing a
simple chunking mechanism wherein we chunk our data into a list of words and about 500 with
about 500 tokens per chunk without any overlap and we can then go ahead and store this chunked data
into a weave artifact so that we can then reuse it later. But then before we do that, we also need to
make our text tokenization safe. Sometimes text contains special tokens that interfere with the
model's tokenization process and it's always a good practice to remove these special tokens.
These special tokens might be tokens like end of text and start of text so depending on the
model's tokenizer you might have to build a special you know cleaning process and in this
case we've built in a cleaning process based on Cohere's tokenizer because that will be the model
we are going to be using the Cohere command R model. We can then now that we've cleaned this
data set we can then store this data set into a weave artifact and you can see a snapshot of what
this artifact looks like. You should also have a similar artifact once you run this colab in
your own environment. Now that we have our clean data set we can go ahead and vectorize the data.
Vectorization is a simple process of converting our data into numerical representations so that
we can then go ahead and retrieve this data based on a new query from a user and in this case we
are using a simple vectorizer the tfidf vectorizer. We're just matching terms based off of the
keywords that are there in a query to the keywords that are there in a document and we can store this
as a weave model. A weave model is a simple way to wrap your data and your code and logic so that
you can then version your application in a more systematic way as you track your experiments.
In this case you can see that our tfidf retriever class has an index data method where we take in
index it using a tfidf vectorizer from scikit-learn and then we also provide a search
method wherein we use cosine distance to calculate the cosine distance between the input
query and the existing documents and then retrieve the top k documents and return them
for a given query. Now that we have our tfidf retriever we can then index our data and you know
run it on a simple query like in this case I've run it on a simple query as how do I use
w and v to log metrics in my training script and it does pretty well by retrieving you know
documents from our technical faq and documents from our logging faq. This is a good baseline to
start off with. Now that we have these retrieved documents we are then ready for generating a
response from our lm. To generate a response from our lm we'll create a simple weave model
that is a simple response generator. It will take in our user query the context that we've retrieved
and then you know use an instruction to finally generate an output. In this case our instruction
is pretty simple we say answer the following question about weights and biases provide an
helpful and complete answer based only on the provided documents. You can go ahead and play
with these instructions yourself by changing the initial prompt and once you pass this to your
response generator you should be able to get a response from the cohere command r model.
Now that we have our response generator ready we can put it all together into a simple rag pipeline.
This pipeline does nothing but you know it combines the two steps the retrieval step and
the response generation step. It takes in a query retrieves the required documents from our retriever
and then passes it on to the lm to generate a response. Putting together the rag pipeline is
pretty straightforward again and you know running the rag pipeline generates a final answer based
off of the response from the lm. Since we have instrumented all of this code with weave already
you should see a dashboard like this once you have published once you click on this link and
the dashboard should show you the nested calls that we have in our rag pipeline starting from
the rag pipeline predict that takes in the user query and generates an output to the retriever
predict which shows your retrieved documents based on the query and the response generator
predict which which shows the query and the context as inputs and the response generated by
the llm. So to sum up in this chapter we've seen how we can take some data process pre-process it
do some cleaning create a simple retriever and create a simple response generator based off of
cohere's command model and generate and create a rag pipeline by putting it all together.
We've also seen how we can utilize weights and biases weave to track and log traces of our llm
calls and track and version our data sets and models. In the next chapter we will see how we
can build upon these aspects and create more complex and advanced systems.