Welcome back to another new chapter where we will be discussing ideas to improve our
retriever's quality and talk more about advanced retriever and re-ranking techniques.
I will first try to motivate the need to go beyond simple retriever systems and argue
that just naively retrieving some pieces of information is not enough for complex queries.
We will be discussing ideas to improve the retrieval by doing query translation.
In this chapter, Charles from Weaviate is going to dig deeper into production, grade retrieval
system and hybrid system.
Meor from Cohere will be digging into RAG system with access to tool calls like web
search or querying SQL database.
Together we will hopefully be covering most of the advanced techniques for retrieval.
Let's revisit retrieval.
In chapter 3 Bharat talked about the idea of indexing where we will use an embedding
model to convert a list of process documents or chunks to vector representations for embeddings.
The collection of documents and its vector representation is called a vector store.
Retrieval happens during query time where the user query is first embedded using the
same embedding model or technique that was used during indexing.
A similarity function like cosine similarity is used to find the top k closest embeddings
in the vector store.
The top k embeddings are mapped back to the corresponding chunks of text.
These texts are semantically similar to the user query.