Let me present a few arguments outlining the limitations of a simple retrieval system.
We start off with the embedding. TF-IDF and BM25-based embedding have limited capacity to
capture different contexts of the same word. Thus, we need deep neural network-based embeddings
that are trained on billions of tokens. The second argument is on misalignment.
Usually, user queries lack the precise language or structure that aligns seamlessly with the
wording of relevant documents. Furthermore, a simple query when embedded have a better
chance of finding a suitable piece of context during retrieval. What is van-db can be answered
using the first paragraph of our documentation, whereas a complex query which can be mapped to
different sections of our documentation would not be able to find all the pieces of relevant
information. We will go into argument 4, but just so you know that the position of relevant chunk
is important.