For complex or multi-step QA tasks,
retrieval with chain of thought reasoning
is getting a lot of traction.
The idea is same as retrieval with decomposition,
but instead of breaking down the query into sub-questions
in the first LLM call,
we first retrieve relevant documents for a query Q.
We then prompt LLM to read the query and documents
to come up with reasoning sentence T1 and retrieve for it.
We keep retrieving and reasoning
till termination step is met.
In this case, determination is the presence of the answer,
is substring.
You can come up with different complexities of retrieval
with chain of thought reasoning.