Now let's look at re-ranking in action.
In this Colab notebook for chapter five,
we first do the setup, import relevant packages,
initialize Weave, and then download the chunked data.
The idea here is to compare the DenseRetriever
and DenseRetrieverWithReranker.
We first initialize the DenseRetriever
and index the chunked data.
We set up evaluation using Weave Evaluation
like we showed in chapter two.
We do the same with DenseRetrieverWithReranker,
initialize it, index the chunked data, and then evaluate it.
We'll go to the evaluation comparison in a second,
but let's look into the re-ranker
and how we are doing retrieval with re-ranker.
You can see the Cohere re-ranker here
uses the Cohere client,
and we send the data to the Cohere API.
The data here are the query,
the documents that we want to compare against,
and the top end.
These are the number of chunks we want to return back
after re-ranking.
The DenseRetrieverWithReranker
first retrieves top-k context
and then uses the re-ranker to return top-nchunks.
This is what is fed to our LLM for response synthesis.
I've already evaluated the DenseRetriever
and DenseRetrieverWithReranker.
Let's compare both.
As you can see, the DenseRetriever,
which is in purple color,
has a lower hit rate at MRR
compared to the DenseRetrieverWithReranker.
It is slightly better in terms of NDGC and MAP,
but overall, if you look at the F1 score,
our DenseRetrieverWithReranker
is exceeding the DenseRetriever,
which means both the recall and the precision
are well-balanced.