In cases where we have multiple sources of information,
we not only retrieve information from a single vector store,
but can do so over multiple vector stores.
Depending on use case or business constraints,
we can even use conventional SQL databases
or consider doing web search.
We do all this by using a concept called routing.
Besides jargon, the underlying idea is simple.
We take in the user query and use an LLM function calling ability
to select the retrieval sources.
Based on a recent study,
it is best if we use one LLM call to come up with a reasoning step
to select data sources and use another LLM call to do function calling.