Well, this is the end of this chapter.
To summarize, there aren't any silver bullets,
so experiment and evaluate with different retrieval techniques.
For complex queries, try breaking down the query into smaller subqueries
or rewrite the query to improve the recall of your retrieval system.
Metadata filtering helps speed up retrieval time
and enforce correct information to be picked.
Don't be afraid to create multiple vector databases
or retrieve using different algorithms,
because we can re-rank different retrieved contexts
to improve the recall.
However, this is a slow technique,
so reciprocal rank fusion is a better way or a quicker way
to select the best chance across multiple retrieval techniques,
which can also be followed with Cohere re-ranking.
I hope you learned something new and exciting in this chapter.
Thank you.