Now let's look at the hybrid retriever in action.
The hybrid retriever re-ranker class
combines both the BM25 retriever and dense retriever.
The idea is to first retrieve top-key documents
using both the retriever.
We then use the reciprocal rank fusion to fuse the results
and then use Cohere re-ranker to rank
and then select top-n documents for our query.
Let's index the chunk data
and set up evaluation using Weave evaluation
using the metrics we have been using so far.
Let's compare the hybrid retriever re-ranker
with dense retriever as well as dense retriever with re-ranker.
This is our evaluation comparison dashboard.
The negative values here show that our hybrid retriever re-ranker
is performing better compared to the other two retrievers.
The hit rate is 60% compared to 31% and 48% respectively
for the other two retrievers.
We also improved the F1 score over the dense retriever
as well as dense retriever with re-ranker.
All this at the cost of a higher model of tendency,
which is obvious.