In order to handle complex queries, we have a few strategies collectively called query translation.
The basic idea is to modify the query such that it can improve the recall of the retrieval and in-process help answer complex queries.
Depending on the use case, we can consider the following strategies.
We can use an LLM to rewrite the original query into multiple similar queries with slight modification.
This can help improve the misalignment problem.
Another strategy is to decompose the user query into smaller or simpler queries called sub-queries.
The query enhancer, Bharat discussed in chapter 4, uses this strategy. This can help answer complex queries.
Another idea is to convert the query to a high-level abstract query, retrieve for it, and generate an abstract response.
Then use this abstract answer in documents to reason about the original query.
This method can be useful if you care a lot about the factual consistency of the response.
Let's look at the retrieval steps for one such query translation strategy.
In the last chapter, query enhancer decomposed the query into sub-queries and then retrieved for all the sub-queries together.
Alternatively, we can also retrieve sequentially.
We first use an LLM to figure out intermediate sub-problems that can solve the main question.
We sequentially retrieve for one sub-problem, generate an answer for it, and do it sequentially till all the sub-problems are answered.
We can then use these intermediate answers to solve the main question.