Now let's look at the fourth argument I made about the position of the relevant context.
After we do cosine similarity between the query embedding and all the document embeddings,
we then sort it in descending order. Note that this ordering will not necessarily surface all
the relevant information. Say there are six relevant pieces of information. If we take the
top three chunks, we only have one relevant chunk, thus the recall is 0.167. Taking the top five
chunks improves the recall to 0.4. If we take top 10 chunks, the recall will be 0.667. You get the
point. The more we take from this ordered list of documents, the better the recall. But obviously
there ain't any free lunch. More context increases the latency and the cost of the pipeline.
Moreover, we know from control study that the position of the relevant context is crucial for
the LLM to properly attend to it. In the Lost in the Middle paper, the authors change the position
of the most relevant document from the first position till the 20th. Clearly the performance
is highest when the relevant information occurs at the beginning or at the end of the input context
and significantly degrades when models must access relevant information in the middle of long
contexts. In our top k equals 10 retrieve context, two of the relevant pieces of information are in
middle which will obviously impact the quality of the generated response.