Let's kick things off by understanding response synthesis and prompting.
Think of response synthesis as the translator in your RAG system.
It takes the raw data and transforms it into a user-friendly answer.
It's the bridge between what your system retrieves and what the user sees.
Now, prompting is like giving your LLM a really good instruction manual.
It guides the LLM's behavior, ensuring that it generates relevant and friendly responses.
In wandbot, we've seen firsthand how crucial these elements are.
The beauty of effective prompting is its versatility.
It allows RAG systems like wandbot to handle a wide range of queries,
ranging from simple questions to complex technical issues.