We found few-shot prompting to be highly effective in our RAG system.
Few-shot learning bridges the gap between zero-shots approaches and fine-tuning.
By providing a small set of examples within the prompt,
we enabled the model to quickly adapt to specific tasks.
Here's the process we followed while implementing this in wandbot.
We carefully selected representative examples covering common query types and desired response formats.
The key is balancing diversity with specificity to our use cases.
Ensuring that wandbot can handle a wide range of queries while maintaining expertise in the Weights & Biases documentation.
The impact has been significant.
We achieved a 6% overall performance boost, increasing from 66% to 72% in terms of answer correctness.
This improvement encompasses more accurate responses, better code snippets, and enhanced user satisfaction.
Few-shot prompting has proven particularly effective for domain-specific applications like documentation assistance.
It's a valuable technique to consider when optimizing your RAG system for improved performance and adaptability.
Moving on to the nitty-gritty of few-shot prompting,
I want to share some key practices that can really boost your RAG system's performance.
At the top of our list is using high-quality, diverse examples.
It's crucial to tailor these examples to common query types.
This prepares your system to handle the most frequent user needs with precision.
Now, here's where it gets tricky.
You need to balance performance with token usage.
And finally, keep your example set dynamic.
As your system grows, so should your examples.
Regularly update and ensure your system stays in tune with the evolving use cases.
These practices have been a game-changer for wandbot,
helping us maintain top-notch responses while adapting to shifting user needs.
The key takeaway? Guide your model effectively, but don't overwhelm it.
Implement these practices, and you'll see a significant uplift in your RAG system's capabilities.