When it comes to quality control in RAG systems, we focus on three key elements
guardrails, grounding, and citations.
Think of output guardrails as your system's safety net.
We use structural checks, semantic filters, and safety measures
to keep responses on topic and appropriate.
Grounding techniques are all about anchoring the responses in facts.
For example, in wandbot, we tightly couple the responses with our documentation
and fact check against our knowledge base.
This has reduced hallucinations and improved response accuracy significantly.
Citations are our transparency tool.
By including links and in-text references, we have enhanced user trust
and users appreciate being able to verify information themselves.
The impact on wandbot has evolved from a basic query system
to a trusted documentation assistant.
For example, when explaining complex features,
it now provides accurate step-by-step guidance with verifiable sources.
Remember, these techniques work together to create a robust, trustworthy RAG system.
Implement them consistently and you will see a marked improvement
in output quality and user satisfaction.