We'll now look at a few advanced prompting techniques.
These strategies are where RAG systems start to really flex their muscles.
First is Chain of Thought Prompting.
It helps the LLM break down complex problems into step-by-step solutions.
Next we have Self-reflection Prompting.
Here's where an LLM double checks its own work and refines its responses for improved
accuracy.
Next we have Tree of Thought Prompting.
This technique allows your LLM to explore multiple reasoning paths simultaneously,
much like a chess player considering various moves simultaneously.
These techniques pack a punch in terms of benefits.
They sharpen the reasoning skills, tackle complex queries with ease, and produce nuanced
and more context-aware responses.
But here's the catch.
With the increased power comes increased complexity.
You might find yourself juggling token limitations and intricate prompt designs.
The secret sauce is finding the right balance for your specific use case.
For those hungry for more, we have a full course dedicated to these techniques.
Check out the link in the description to dive deeper into this fascinating world.