Let's dive into some best practices for system prompt iteration.
These are the habits that separate a good drag system from great ones.
First up, version control.
Treat your prompts like code.
Track changes and their impacts.
It's a lifesaver when you need to roll back or understand what worked.
Next, schedule regular performance reviews.
Catch issues early and keep improving consistently.
Next, involve your whole team.
Developers, domain experts, designers.
They all bring unique perspectives.
And in our experience, this cross-functional approach is what leads to more robust solutions.
And lastly, document everything.
Write down why you've made each refinement.
It builds your team's knowledge base and saves time in the long run.
Again, consistency is key.
Implement these practices and you'll see your drag system evolve and improve over time.