Hello and welcome to this walkthrough of chapter 6 of our RAG course where we'll be focusing on
response synthesis and prompting techniques. First, we'll set up our environment and load
the chunk data like we did in the previous chapters. With the initial setup out of the way,
let's jump straight into the core concepts. Our goal is to improve the response quality through
iterative prompt engineering. We'll start with a baseline prompt and make several improvements.
So here's our baseline prompt. It's simple and provides basic instructions.
Let's run our evaluation and see how it performs. As we can see, our baseline scores gives us a good
starting point for the comparison. In our first iteration, we've added more precise instructions.
We've defined a role, included a few dynamic elements, and provided a structured approach
for responses. You should notice that upon running evaluations, there is a marked improvement in the
response metrics. For our second iteration, we'll include an example output in the system prompt.
This demonstrates proper formatting, citation use, and the expected level of detail to the LLM.
Upon running evaluations, we should see some improvements in the metrics,
again showing us the value of providing a concrete example to the LLM.
In our third iteration, we have incorporated model reasoning. We are now asking the model
to explain its thought process and break down complex queries. Again, this approach should lead
to significant improvements in our response quality metrics. And for our final iteration,
we'll keep the same prompt but switch to a more advanced language model.
This demonstrates how combining refined prompts with better models can yield synergistic improvements.
Now let's compare our results across these iterations. We can see a clear trend of improvement
in response quality with some trade-offs in latency for later iterations. To wrap up what
we've learned, iterative prompt engineering significantly enhances response quality.
Structured instructions and examples guide the model effectively.
Encouraging reasoning transparency leads to more trustworthy responses and combining refined
prompts with advanced models yields the best results. It's crucial to balance response quality
with system efficiency. Remember, RAG system development is an ongoing process. Continuously
analyze, refine, and optimize your prompts and model selection for the best results.
That's all for this chapter and thank you for watching.