Let's wrap up with some troubleshooting tips and best practices.
Even the best RAG systems face challenges, but with the right approach, we can overcome them.
Common issues include incoherent responses, struggles with ambiguous queries,
and inconsistency across topics.
For improving coherence, we use structured prompts to guide logical flow.
It's like giving your LLM a roadmap for its responses.
When dealing with ambiguous queries, clarification prompts are what you need.
They help your system ask for more information when needed.
To maintain consistency, regular knowledge base updates are crucial.
Keep your system's information fresh and aligned.
These techniques aren't just theoretical.
In wandbot, they've improved the response coherence and halved our irrelevant responses.
Remember, troubleshooting is an ongoing process.
Stay vigilant, keep refining, and your RAG system will continue to improve over time.
By implementing these practices, you're not just fixing problems,
you're building a robust, reliable system that can handle whatever the user throws at them.